Contact

4695437812 (Mobile) mwaniki59@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/gideon-mwaniki (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Customer Service
Troubleshooting
Account Management

Languages

English Swahili

Certifications
ALL-LINE ADJUSTING

Gideon Mwaniki

Founder, CTO

Plano, Texas

Summary

I am an IT professional, having experience with troubleshooting from hardware such as cabling to assembling components of a computer such as NIC cards, hard drives, coolant systems to software installation and configuration etc. Also have experience in coding websites and designing from scratch. I find it to be smooth transition in gaining new skills, and relaying the information to the correct people based on the best of practices as possible. I am here for the enhancement of my professional skills in a dynamic and stable workplace, to solve problems in an effective and creative manner in a challenging position.

Experience

Xselarate
Co-Founder, CTO
December 2018 - Present
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

BxMark Founder January 2015 - Present Dallas/Fort Worth Area

At BxMark we provide you w/ Brand development, web sites with UI and UX design, and advertising. Developing brand strategy and strategic consulting tailored for you. Advising new businesses with exclusive information, drafting privacy policies.

Fujitsu Global
Project Coordinator II
September 2018 - December 2018 (4 months)
Richardson, Texas

RealPage, Inc. Lead Developer April 2018 - September 2018 (6 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

First Cash Financial Services, Inc. IT Analyst April 2017 - December 2017 (9 months)

April 2017 December 2017 (o monti

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

DFW New Beginnings
Web Programmer
April 2016 - April 2017 (1 year 1 month)
Bedford, TX

Great Lakes Higher Education Corporation and Affiliates Senior Specialist

June 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 7 months)

Plano

Being knowledgeable, helpful, and caring, dependable, energetic, self-motivated, non-judgmental, team player. enjoy listening, educating, solving problems, and showing borrowers why a particular course of action will help them maintain their accounts in good standing with their student loans. Assisting with any course of action such as consolidation, bankruptcy, returning to school, payments, and loan forgiveness

Achievements: Received 100% Quality and customer service feedback reports consistently for 7 months. Assisted IT admin with multiple corporate responsibilities such as installing hard drives, PXE image booting from servers and load profile information for new hires. Trained new hires, also current employees on new policy changes in class during meetings

Great Lakes Higher Education Corporation and Affiliates Borrower Representative April 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 9 months)

Problem solving resources for our student loan borrowers. answering their questions, assisting borrowers whose accounts are past due, and work to find payment solutions that work for them.

QuikTrip Store Associate February 2014 - June 2014 (5 months) Plano, Texas

Fast and friendly customer service, store presentation and cleanliness, food and product inventory

Time Warner Cable Field Technician July 2013 - January 2014 (7 months)

Installation/ wiring of cable, internet and phone, customer service, troubleshooting, daily reports, making inbound and outbounding calls to customer, dispatch and Time Warner Cable.

Toys R Us
Back of house lead
September 2011 - August 2013 (2 years)

Funiture and blind clearance center Assistant Manager January 2011 - September 2011 (9 months) Plano, Texas

Filling payroll, Sales, deliveries from manufactures, store appearance, having great leadership roll, managing inventory.

Education

Property Adjusting Academy Insurance, 3.0 · (2013 - 2013)

Collin County Community College Associate's degree, General Studies · (2012 - 2013)